以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将有助于MIT开放课程继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，我们走了
okay here we go
今天的所有设置和两个主题是
all set and two topics for today one is
回到SRA教授的演讲
to go back to Professor SRA's lecture
这是上周五，他答应了
that was last Friday and he promised a
定理和证明，今天早上他
theorem and proof and this morning he
把它发给我，这就是收敛
sent it to me so it's the convergence
它证明了它的融合
it's proving the convergence of
随机梯度下降和真的
stochastic gradient descent and really
什么是重要的可能和有用的不是
what's important maybe and useful is not
这么多的证明细节
so much the details of the proof which
我只是学习但是假设
I'm just learning but the assumptions
你知道这里的逻辑是什么
you know what's the logic here what do
你必须假设渐变到
you have to assume about the gradient to
以及获得该算法的算法
and about the algorithm to get the
回答，但现在我回头看
answer and but now I actually look back
在他的演讲视频中，它是
at the video of his lecture and it was
优秀的，我看它有
excellent and as I look at it there were
讲座后面的几件事
a couple of things later in the lecture
我认为会做出很好的项目
that I thought would make good projects
所以我不知道是否有人仍然开放
so I don't know if anybody is still open
如何在项目上做什么，但在这里
to what to do on a project but here here
是我的两个想法，如果你是的话
are my two ideas and and if you if
你已经完成了你的项目
you've already finished your project
通过考虑其中一个来获得A+
well get an A+ by considering one of
这些让你记住，这将是
these so you remember and this will
提醒你讲课的内容
remind you of the of the lecture which
是一件好事，所以你记得那个
is a good thing so you remember that
问题一是是否在
question one was whether in the
随机部分你做完之后
stochastic part do you after you've
取样
sampled
一个或一些小批量，但让我们只是
one or some mini batch but let's just
说一个
say one
损失函数来自一个
of the loss functions coming from one
样本你还记得整点
sample you remember the whole point is
如果我们做的所有zillions样品
that if we do all zillions samples at
每次迭代我们真的很慢
every iteration we're really really slow
所以随机的想法是随机的
so the stochastic idea is to randomly
挑选一个或一小批样品
pick one or a mini batch of the samples
并且只是减少他们的损失就交易
and and just reduce their loss just deal
与他们的损失说平方损失
with their the loss say the square loss
或者稍后我们会看到交叉熵损失
or later we'll see cross-entropy loss
但无论成本如何，只需做一些
but whatever the cost is just do a few
或一个然后问题是在之后
or one and then the question was after
你完成了那个你把它放回去的那个
you've done that one you put it back in
锅和你每次品尝
the pot and every time you sample over
整个系列，但那是
the whole collection but that's
贵或者你只是列出一个
expensive or do you just make a list of
所有的随机顺序的随机列表
random list of random order of all the
样品并通过它们
samples and go through them which is
然后没有替换，这是排序
then without replacement which is sort
那是半非法的
of semi illegal that is the the the
随机化中的逻辑问你
logic in in the randomization asks you
每次更换，但没有人这样做
to replace every time but nobody does it
等待成本可能不值得
wait costs a lot probably not worth it
所以这个项目就是你想的
so the project would be suppose you take
一千或说一百
a thousand or say just a hundred hundred
随机数字说你用MATLAB
random numbers say say you use MATLAB
随机只是命令R，所以你得到
random just the command R and so you get
R和平均数为一半的数字
numbers whose averages a half from R and
他们介于0和1之间，所以我们知道什么
they're between 0 & 1 ok so we know what
平均值是让我们计算两个
the average is so let's compute it two
一种方法是不更换，那就是
ways one is by not replacing and that's
有趣的人，你这么做
the interesting one do you so so to take
一百个样本我猜我们知道
a hundred samples well I guess we know
在我们完成之后
that after we've got through the full
百我们准备得到的
hundred we're gonna get exactly the
现在
right now
但无论如何我的问题是
but anyway there my question would be
多大的差别，你看到在
how much difference do you see in in the
最终的方法所以法律规模很大
eventual approach so the law of large
数字我想我们会告诉我们得到一个
numbers I guess would tell us we get a
这些数字的平均值为1/2
average of 1/2 for these numbers with
均匀分布在0和1之间
uniform distribution between 0 and 1
我应该在这里写任何东西吗？
should I be writing anything here
也许我应该没事，所以我就是这样
maybe I should okay so I'm this is
项目一个你选择数字K哪个
project one you pick numbers a K which
R是R并且从R开始均匀地在01上
is R and from R and so uniformly on 0 1
001，然后将我的问题是什么
0 0 1 and then I my question is what
关于收敛到最后的
about convergence to the the final the
平均值是1/2
average is 1/2
它说可能是一个简单的例子，但是
it says maybe too simple an example but
我们可以看到的会发生什么
could we see what happens for the
和你一样的平均收敛
convergence of the average as you either
做替换或不做替换
do replacements or don't do replacements
然后其实我想看一个
and then in fact I would like to see a
看起来像他的那些人
figure that looks like those in his
讲课记得了，他开始了它
lecture t remember he started it
在某处开始然后在这里
somewhere start and then here's the
完成，但你记得那是随机的
finish but you remember that stochastic
梯度下降有点漂亮
gradient descent was kind of a pretty
一开始就很有效了
effective at the beginning well the
开始那些可能是一百
beginning those might be a hundred
迭代每一个Epoque一个运行
iterations each one Epoque one one run
通过完整的数字，然后当它
through the full number but then when it
它开始越来越近了
got to here got closer it started
振作起来，你记得他确定了
oscillating you remember he identified
事物周围的混乱区域
the region of confusion around the thing
我的建议只是我认为那些
well my suggestion is just I think those
您可以访问视频
videos should be accessible to you on
他们是恒星，所以我很乐意
are they on stellar yeah so I'd love to
看到那种行为有些好
see that behavior in some some good
这种行为的例子和一些
examples of that behavior and some
要使用的图片，这将是一个
pictures to use so that would be one
和安德烈斯的想法哦，是的也是
idea with Andres oh yeah that's also
想法的想法是好的开始
idea to idea to is the is the good start
再坏的结束为一个随机
and then the bad finish for a stochastic
渐变血统，当然还有魔力
gradient descent and of course the magic
即使没有这个魔法的话
words in even without this the magic
单词和计算是提前停止
words and computations is early stopping
我们不太适合所以我们想要
we we don't over fit so we wanted to
无论如何早点停下来，提前停下来
stop early anyway and early stopping
就像一个好主意一样
just as like a good idea
因为如果那是什么，那就是
for if that's what if that's what the
接近X星的那个
approach to the to the X star that
你正在寻找这将是
you're looking for the this would be the
地方，这就是这X
place where the this is where that's X
我们是毕业生F和X星的明星
star where we're grad F and X star is
哦，这就是最低点
near oh that's that's the minimum point
那个Arg男人究竟是男人
that's Arg men are men exactly what
我们正在寻找的，我们并不觉得
we're looking for and we don't find it
很好
very well
但我们接近它快好了2
but we get close to it fast okay two
关于项目的想法，所以也许我会
ideas on project so just so maybe I'll
转到今天主题的主题
go to the main topic of today the topic
我答应了反向传播的想法
I promised the idea of back propagation
计算这一切都是为了计算
to compute this is all to compute
gradF梯度所有的导数
grad F the gradient all the derivatives
这是DFDX1到DFDXM
this is this is the DF DX 1 to DF DX M
也许我会说我有MM功能的地方
maybe I'll say where I have M M features
forfor是为了样品好，所以这是
for for is for the sample okay so that's
反向传播就是这样
back propagation and that's the thing
它的发现或重新发现放
whose discovery or rediscovery put
没有那个的地图上的神经网络
neural nets on the map without that's
当然要找到关键的计算方法
the key calculation of course to find
最陡下降的梯度
the gradient in the steepest descent
算法每一步都需要一个渐变
algorithm every step needs a gradient
如果你不能快速计算它
and if you can't compute it quickly
你是个坏人，但是你
you're you're in bad shape so but you
可以通过这种自动计算它
can compute it quickly by this automatic
反向模式的区别
differentiation in Reverse mode which is
否则我不认为那些
otherwise known those I don't think that
人们也许Hinton是第一个
people maybe Hinton was the first was
在深入发展的领导者
the leader in in the in developing deep
神经网络深度学习和他
neural nets deep learning and he
实现了，所以我给了他很大的荣誉
realized so I give him big credit for
该反传会工作，
that back propagation would work and
会给他快速的渐变但是它
would give him fast gradients but it
实际上之前已经研究过
actually had been studied before under
名称ad自动区分所以
the name ad automatic differentiation so
优点只是告诉你这个想法
merit just tell you that idea
有些人可能知道它可能知道
some of you may know it may know about
它可能比我更了解并且可能知道
it may know more than I and might know
好的网站看到这个
good a good website to see this
描述
description
当然还有一部分
there'll be of course a section of the
已经是你的笔记了
book of the notes already you you
已经拥有了它部分，这是
already have it section this is
在7.2中这是深入的章节
in 7.2 so this is the chapter on deep
学习和第一部分是关于
learning and the first section was about
你记得X的结构
the structure of f of X and you remember
关于f结构的关键点
the key point about the structure of f
X是我会从X和开始
of X is that it would I start with X and
应用X的一些函数f1和那个
apply some function f1 of X and to that
我应用了X的一些函数f2
I apply some function f2 of X and to
我应用了F3F3的一些功能
that I apply some function of F 3 F 3 of
XF的1F2，这就是事情
F 2 of F 1 of X and that's the thing
我需要的衍生物，所以我只是
whose derivative I need so I'll just
拿你熟悉的普通衍生物
take ordinary derivative you know well
偏导数真的是因为我
partial derivatives really because I
是的，我最好说的偏导数，以便
yeah I better say partial derivatives so
假设X是一对XY的例子
suppose X is a pair XY example so so
在这里让我通过例子向你展示
here let me show you by example so
假设X的f让我采取简单的方法
suppose f of X is let me take a simple
示例X立方倍X加2y即可
example X cubed times X plus 2y okay so
我想以这种方式思考这个功能
I want to think of that function the way
任何人都会像建造一样
anybody would as being built as the
两个功能的产品，所以有一个
product of two functions so there's a
产品规则进入衍生品
product rule to get into the derivative
然后我们需要每个的衍生物
and then we need the derivatives of each
因此，有一个权力规则和一个
piece so there's a power rule and a
线性和线性组合规则
linear and a linear combination rule so
它有一些我们使用的规则
it's got a few of the rules that we use
并且重点是思考
and point is to think about the
X和f的f的计算
computation of f of X and the
DFDX的计算和计算
computation of DF DX and the computation
DFTY是那些衍生物
of DFT Y those are the derivatives that
我们需要这是我们需要的功能
we need this is the function we need and
如何快速完成这些计算
how to do those computations quickly
好的，这是第7.2节我
okay so and this is section 7.2 which I
从中受益匪浅
which benefited a lot from
博客我不是博客读者或博客
a blog I'm not a blog reader or a blog
作家，但不知何故，我发现这个博客，
writer but somehow I found this blog so
让我把它的克里斯托弗
let me put its Christopher
奥拉夫是他的名字，他真的写道
Olaf is his name and he's really writes
清除事情让他做出贡献
to clear things so he he he contributes
他为一家大公司工作
he works for one of the big companies
你知道更深入的研究吗？
and does you know the deeper research
但他也是一个非常好的暴露者
but he's also a really good expose etre
他现在使用的网站是
and the the website that he now uses is
叫做蒸馏点什么，但我想
called distill dot something but I think
也许这个博客是较早之前的
maybe this blog was earlier before the
开始蒸馏，但可能会加载
start of distill but it might be loaded
到提制反正就是这样的地方
onto distill anyway that's that's where
我得到了这个简单的描述
I got this simple description of
反向传播让我们做微积分
backpropagation let's just do calculus
首先，如果我有一个
for first of all if I just have a
甚至一个变量的功能
function of maybe even one variable
DFDX的衍生物是什么？
what's the derivative what is DF DX here
只是想要记住是什么
just to realize just to remember what is
它
it
我们必须做什么计算DFDX
what calculation we have to do so DF DX
这是n等于一个变量所以
this is with n equal one one variable so
我会使用普通衍生物而不是
I'll I use ordinary derivative and not
偏导数，但这是什么
partial derivative but this is then what
我这就是真的有工作要做，但
I that's what really has to be done but
那是什么的衍生物
just what's the derivative of that of a
当然，功能链很好
chain of functions well of course the
链规则所以椅子是什么的
chain rule so the chair what does the
连锁规则说我区分f3我
chain rule say I differentiate f3 I
不知道是什么我也很好，我把
don't know what do I well well I put
它与...有所区别
that it's differentiated with respect to
f3DF3df2就是我应该放的
f3 DF 3 d f2 is that what I should put
好
ok
我在哪里评估该衍生物
and where do I evaluate that derivative
所以是的，所以我不在X评价它
so so so yeah I don't evaluate it at X
对，我是不同的有效F-所以
right I'm different effective F - so do
我在F的F到X这个评估它
I evaluate it at F to of F 1 of X this
是链规则得到一点点的地方
is where the chain rule gets a little
cheney好吧那我们知道DF2DF1
cheney okay then we know that DF 2 DF 1
现在又在F1处进行了评估
and again that's now evaluated at F 1 of
X然后最终因子是DF1是X.
X and then the final factor is DF 1 be X
在X评估我们是什么
evaluated at X that's somehow what we
必须做，这只是一个
have to do and that's just for an
普通的一个变量函数和我
ordinary one variable function and I
这里有两个变量函数和
have here a two variable function and
深度学习有一百万变量
deep learning has a million variable
功能所以我想我们不会去
function so let's I think we won't go to
一百万，但我们可以管理两个让我们
a million but two we can manage so let's
让我们来计算那些让我们计算的东西吧
let's let's compute those let's compute
该函数首先计算F所以
the function first of all compute F so
我给了X等于2和y等于说
I'm given X equal say 2 and y equals say
3，我将创造一个什么样的
3 and what do I'm gonna create a
计算图所以这只是为了
computational graph so this is just to
画画，所以我确实要走绘制
draw so I'm actually going to draw the
计算图
computational graph
为4f计算然后它将是
to compute for for 4f and then it'll be
找到该图的变体
a variation of that graph to find the
衍生品，但让我们开始吧
derivatives but so let's just start with
该图首先为该函数
the graph first of all for the function
因为我们将再次需要它
because we're gonna need that so again
这是X立方但这么好吧，我写的
it's X cubed but so okay I write that
再次功能X立方次X加2y
function again X cubed times X plus 2y
所以我认为我们要迈出第一步
so I think we're going to the first step
将找到X加X立方体
will be to find X plus X cubed that
因素将是8，我们必须
factor which will be 8 and we have to
找到另一个因素X加2y然后
find the other factor X plus 2y so then
我要去那里使用Y和X这些
I'm going to that uses Y and X so these
是其向前发展的有向图
are its a directed graph going forward
用这个计算使得X加2y
with this computation so X plus 2 y
等于它是两个和六个哦
equals whatever it is two and six oh
八再没有辉煌
eight again not brilliant
我在这里要改变的是3y3y
what shall I change here make it 3 y 3y
只是在这里所以得到不同数量
just to get a different number here so
现在X是2y是3我得到11这是一个很好的
now X is 2 y is 3 I get 11 that's a good
数
number
好到目前为止这么好，现在是下一步
ok so far so good and now the next step
在这张图上将是我有一个
on this graph will be to I have a
那些将要去的产品
product of those so that will go to the
产品F等于1188的8倍
product F equals 8 times 1188
好的，所以我们得到答案88你愿意吗？
ok so we've got the answer 88 would you
通常我不会那么乱
which mess normally I wouldn't take that
计算F的大部分书
much of a book to compute F
我会说2个立方次2加3
I would have said 2 cubed times 2 plus 3
第3次，我已经简化了
times 3 and I'd have simplified that to
8次11，如果是的话，我会得到88次
8 times 11 and I would have got 88 so if
我们只是正常写作会
we were just writing normally that would
做到这一点，但是这是对图片
do it but this is the picture of the
计算图确定好不错
computational graph ok good good good
现在它是衍生品的两个衍生品
now it's the derivatives two derivatives
假设我们在fdy中找到FDX
to find the F DX in the f dy suppose we
先行前进
go forward first
我的观点将会是伟大的
my point is going to be or the great
重点是落后是更好的逆转
point is that backward is better reverse
模式更好，但我们不知道是什么
mode is better but we don't know what
这意味着直到我们向前迈进
that means until we've gone forward so
让我继续前进，所以现在我要走了
let me go forward so now I'm gonna go
向前
forward
[掌声]
[Applause]
那么我们怎样才能让FDX好呢
so what do we what let's do the F DX ok
每个人都对DFDX有所了解
everybody's up for DF DX the partial
衍生规格2x所以这里我们有X.
derivative spec 2x so here we have X
等于2和y等于3
equal 2 and y equals 3
好的，然后我必须认为我采取
okay and then I've got to figure I take
该步骤的衍生物是第一个
the derivative of that step the first
步骤是X2x立方，所以我需要
step was X 2x cubed so I need the
衍生广告的全部意义在于
derivative the whole point of ad is that
计算的每次计算
the computation every computation of a
衍生品像这样打破了
derivative breaks down like this and a
非常简单的作品和衍生品
very simple pieces and the derivatives
那些简单的部分也很简单
of those simple pieces are also simple
碎片所以重点是打破
pieces so the whole point is to break
要适当地替换那里
the to replace appropriately the there
是那些中间步骤
was those intermediate steps with
导数，以便计算X.
derivatives so so as to compute the X
所以我必须使用这个事实
derivative so so I have to use the fact
x的导数与...相关
that the derivative of x cubed with
尊重X哦我最好做偏
respect to X oh I better do partial
X立方体的衍生部分凹槽
derivative partial grooves of X cubed
加标2x或3x平方所以现在我就是我
spiked 2x or 3x squared so now I'll I'm
抱歉，可能是一个公式，然后是一个
sorry up put maybe a formula and then a
号码，以便给出给出3倍
number so that gives that gives 3 times
412和x立方的衍生物
4 12 and the derivative of x cubed with
尊重Y给出0然后再给出
respect to Y gives 0 right and then the
导数所以我正在做X衍生物
derivative so I'm doing the X derivative
所以Y的导数相对于X.
so the derivative of Y with respect to X
如果我是的，你能告诉我吗？
is you get to tell me if I'm if I'm
计算偏导数是0是0
computing partial derivatives is 0 is 0
Y和X是独立的，就是这样
Y and X are independent and that's this
在我看来，原因，
is the reason in my view that the
前进的方法是浪费，因为
forward method is is wasteful because
我要做另一个
I'm gonna have to do another
其他y导数的图表
graph for the y derivative in other
跟踪跟踪x的单词
words tracking the tracking the x
衍生品从来没有很多东西
derivatives a whole lot of stuff never
离开地面，所以它永远不应该
got off the ground so it never should
无论如何都看着它，但我做到了
have looked at it so anyway but I do
需要
need
我会有这个X加3y所以也许我
I'll have this X plus 3y so maybe I
不知道是否消除，我认为
don't know whether to erase that I think
我只是因为我不知道该怎么做
I will just because I don't know what to
是的，所以现在就让我吧
do with it there yeah so now now let me
拿那些我真正需要的是
take the ones that I really need is
关于x加X的导数
derivative with respect to X of x plus
3Y为1，因此，让我
3y which is 1 and so that gives me the
回答1对任何X实际上还好，现在
answer 1 for any X actually okay and now
什么
what
哦，我是的，我真的不需要这些
oh I yeah I'm really I don't need these
这是浪费时间不是吗
the this is a waste of time isn't it
是否只有我想要的X衍生物
is it only X derivatives I want anyway
让我们继续吧
let's just keep going
你可以看到这需要一点点
you can see this takes a little
组织，我没有练习
organization and I'm not practiced with
它所以我要做什么我正在寻找
it so what am I going to do I'm looking
对于我的X衍生得使用
for the X derivative of I've got to use
现在我找到了产品规则X.
a product rule now I found the X
该因子的导数是X的12
derivative of that factor was 12 the X
该因子的导数是1，现在
derivative of this factor is 1 and now
产品的X衍生物也是如此
the X derivative of the product so so
现在我要做某种产品规则
now I'm gonna do a somehow product rule
这个产品的X衍生物我
the the X derivative of this product I
给这两个术语起一个名字
sort of given these two terms a name
让我打电话让我先打个电话
let let me call let me call that first
术语X立方体和第二个术语
term X cube and the second term
x+31：f所以我会称之为两个
x + 3 1 : f so I'll call that the two
这两个术语CNS所以我现在需要得到我
the two terms CNS so I now need to get I
现在需要得到这样的CD
now need to get so that's the CD s this
是DCDX这是DCDX和这个
is DC DX right this is DC DX and this
一个是dsDX和CD我为什么需要
one is d s DX and the CD why do I need
知道我很抱歉我是这个
to know that I'm sorry I'm this
计算图已经抛出了我但是
computational graph has thrown me but
现在我想使用产品规则
now now I want to use the product rule
而且我正在使用X衍生物，所以我
and I'm taking X derivatives right so I
应该有计算C和s啊是的我
should have computed C and s ah yes I
看到我有你需要的那些
see I've got a you need those in the
产品规则，所以我应该计算
product rule so I should have computed
看到8+s是正确的5
see as being 8 + s as being 5 that right
2+311是的，我需要八个人
2 + 3 11 yeah I needed the eight in the
哦，我刚刚开始跑步了
oh what's up I've just been running
在这里没有让自己进入
along here without getting myself in the
整个图片是的8和11是对的但是
whole picture yeah 8 and 11 is right but
现在我正在寻找衍生品
now I'm looking for the derivatives
对，所以我不会增加那些
right so I don't multiply those that's
不是产品规则所以产品规则
not the product rule so the product rule
是什么时候这样的产品规则
is what s times so so this product rule
我应该做这个组合
I should I have to do this combination
这是现在的产品规则
of this is now the product rule for the
C次的衍生物，所以我想要CD
derivative of C times s so I want C D s
DX+sDCDX我想我现在正在进行中
DX + s DC DX I think I'm on track now
现在我想输入数字
and now I want to put in numbers
所以C是8，SDX我们计算了Ds
so C is 8 the SDX have we computed D s
DX是的，DX是1而现在是自己的
DX yes the s DX is 1 and now s itself is
计算为11和DCDX我们计算为
computed as 11 and DC DX we computed as
12II不敢看有我我我
12 I I don't dare look have I am I am i
我不认为我会得到哦不，我
I don't think I'm gonna get oh no I
不知道答案是什么，但对不起我
don't know what the answer yet sorry I'm
不要试图让你们得到88分
not trying to get 88 right you guys are
没有帮助你看到我遇到麻烦但是
not helping you see I'm in trouble but
我在这里想象的是8
what I what I imagine here is that's 8
那是132所以我得到了140公顷
and that's 132 so I'm getting 140 ha is
有可能那就是
there any possibility that that's the
正确答案
right answer
对于DFDX的D，这是DFDXI.
for D for D F D X this is DF DX I
通过观察我的斗争来计算你
computed you by watching me struggle
在这里，你看到了我每一步的想法
here you're seeing the idea I every step
我采取每一步的衍生物
I take the derivative of each step so it
是一个功率步骤X立方体所以我有一个3倍
was a power step X cube so I had a 3x
平方和一步，所以我有一个1
squared and a some step so I had a 1
然后我下一步是
then I the next step was a
乘法，所以我需要产品
multiplication so I needed the product
规则我将这些分开
rule for that I have these separate
数字，所以我把它们放进去，所以它是一个
numbers so I put them in and so it's a
我们只完成了计算图
the computational graph finished we only
需要两个级别，我们得到8和130
needed two levels and we got 8 and 130
140可以，但我们没有得到FD为什么
to 140 okay but we didn't get the FD why
是的，为此，我需要另一个需要
yes and for that I'd need another need
再次重做这个，我不想
to redo this again and I don't want to
这样做我宁愿反过来
do that I would rather do the reverse
模式并立即那就是做这两个动作
mode and do them both at once that's the
河的一点
point of the river
抚平的效率非常高这是很
smooth it's very efficient it's very
高效的实际计算
efficient actually computing the
完成后完成渐变
gradient after you've done the done the
首先为功能计算工作
work for the function computing first
衍生工具，你可以计算出N个第一
derivatives you could compute n first
约四或五的衍生物
derivatives with about like four or five
倍的成本不会结束倍，这是
times the cost not end times that that's
对我来说很神奇
amazing to me
这是我可以计算的惊人
that is amazing that that I can compute
梯度非常有效地通过将其通过
the gradient very efficiently by it by
后面的道具所以我必须这样做
the back prop so I have to you have to
告诉你向后的方式，但我是
show you the backwards way but so I'm
只是，只是我只是要跟随
just yeah just I'm just going to follow
所有的路径向后，以便我得到
all the paths backwards so that I get
DFDX和DF都是你看到的
both DF DX and D F dy just by you see
我的想法是采取衍生物
the idea is to take the derivative of
每一步都是真正的小步骤
each step each small step that's really
我们在微积分中做什么你知道如果你
what we do in calculus you know if you
想想微积分的开始
think about the start of a calculus
当然你的衍生品是做什么的
course what do you what derivatives do
我们实际上知道我们实际上是否使用XF
we actually know do we actually use X F
在X加DeltaX减F我们是什么
at X plus Delta X minus F do we what
我们研究出来的衍生品我们做了
derivatives do we grind out we do the
每个微积分的X到N的导数
derivatives of X to the N every calculus
本书以x平方和和。开头
book starts with x squared and and and
找到一个导数X到n然后你
finds a derivative X to the n then you
做正义X和加X然后其他人
do sine X and plus X then what others
还有吗
are there anymore
即使是对X的X好处也是如此
even e to the X good e to the X and it's
新生中的反函数日志
the inverse function log in freshman
微积分你总是写Ln只是为了
calculus you always write Ln just to be
过时没关系，现在可能是
out of date okay and now that may be the
列表是它，然后链规则在那里
list is it and then the chain rule there
还有其他你真正做过的事
are there others that you actually do a
实际上e到X的计算是
computation of actually e to the X is
酒店所定义的其
defined by the property that its
衍生物是X到X然后你
derivative is e to the X and then you
发现X必须是什么，正弦X
discover what log X has to be and sine X
你是怎么做的
you how do you do
X加DeltaX将比较减去
of X plus Delta X will compare minus
X的正弦你怎么找到你知道的
sine of X how do you find the you know
艰难的方式一劳永逸
the hard way once and for all way you
画一个小单位圆圈，然后弄乱
draw a little unit circle and and mess
你会发现一些角度
with some some angles and you discover
该正弦的衍生物是
that the derivative of the sine is the
余弦，如果你已经定义了标志
cosine that's if you've defined the sign
来自右边a的比例
from as a ratio of sides in a in a right
三角形，当然你可以定义它
triangle of course you could define it
作为一个无限的系列然后你会
as an infinite series and then you would
回到刚好那么好用的那样
be back to just using that okay so so
微积分正是我们正在做的事情
calculus does exactly what we're doing
这里通过链找到所有衍生物
here finds all derivatives by the chain
规则适用于它拥有的几个规则
rule applied to a few ones that it has
已经详细研究，但切线
has worked out in detail but tangent of
X我们将使用商法则割线
X we would use the quotient rule secant
我们将使用商一规则
of X we would use the quotient rule one
过余弦和我们使用的产品
over cosine and the products we use the
产品规则所以真正的微积分倾向于
product rule so really calculus tends to
你看的时候看起来相当简单
seem fairly simple after when you look
回来看看你到底做了什么
back to see what actually you did and
然后整合什么是积分
then integration what is integral
关于或多或少猜测的微积分
calculus about more or less guessing the
你必须回答你
answer right you you you have to
集成了XDX的f
integrate f of X DX
你真的和你有什么关系
and you have so really what you what you
要做的就是想想什么
have to do is sort of think okay what
有这个衍生物有什么功能
had this derivative what function had
那衍生物和乱七八糟的东西
that derivative and mess around and get
它真的是它呃它就是它
it so that's really it's uh it's it's a
新生当然我觉得还好，所以我在哪里
freshman course I guess okay so where am
一世
I
向后右，这是仍然的事情
backward right that's the thing still to
如何落后的系统工作
do how does the backward system work
好吧，我会尽力尝试
okay I'll try it try my best
好的，所以这里是这个大目标
okay so here's the here's the big goal
返回所以反向模式广告权利让我
back so reverse mode ad right and let me
让自己有点注意
make myself a little note a little
没注意再给你一个
little notice to give you another
您执行订单的示例
example where the order that you do the
计算有很大的不同我
computations makes a big difference I
意思是这不是很明显，这将
mean and that's not obvious that it will
对，数学中有很多东西
right there are many things in math that
你可以按任何顺序做它
you could do in either order and it it
从逻辑上看，你已经完成了
seems like logically you've done the
同样的事情，另一个和另一个
same things so another another and
更简单的例子，显示了一种方式
simpler example which shows how one way
可能比另一个快得多
could be fast away faster than another
方式是当我将两个矩阵相乘时
way is when I'm multiplying two matrices
三个矩阵，所以我乘三
three matrices so I'm multiplying three
矩阵B次C和C
matrices a times B times C and the
问题是我先做BC然后再做
question is do I do B C first and then
乘以a或者我先做B和
multiply by a or do I do a B first and
再乘上C和当然，我的
then multiply that by C and of course I
按照ABC的顺序保持它们的顺序
kept them in order in the order ABC but
计算的顺序可以是
the order of computations can be
不同的是你得到的相同
different then you get the same you get
正确回答两种方式，但那些可以
the right answer both ways but those can
完全不同的一个
be completely completely different one
可一千倍比快
can be a thousand times faster than the
其他所以这只是为了显示它
other so that's just to show actually it
有点连接到这个
kind of connects to this and there is
还有另外一个，所以我也会这样做
also another so I'll I'll do that too
而这也是这个例子
and there's also this so this is example
这意味着两个例子
example two where this is meant to be
示例一和示例三将是
example one and example three would be
它会导致称为伴随的东西
it leads to something called the adjoint
微分方程中的方法
method in in in differential equations
或者在计算中的优化
or in in optimization in in computing in
最大化计算最佳-是的
computing optimum in maximizing - yeah
并且具有相同的他们是真的
and that has the same they're really the
它提高速度的根本原因是
underlying reason it gives a speed up is
它在产品中做出了正确的选择
it makes the right choice in a product
三件事是的，这样就足够了
of three things yeah so it'll be enough
做一个例子-好吧让
to do example one an example - okay let
我一个小时的例子
me go with the example one hour all
这是现在的反向传播
right this is now back propagation
最后我们做到了没关系，所以我该怎么做
finally we got to it okay so how do i
我如何嗯，我看我看我的
how do i well i look at my look at my
注意到我这样做是好的
notes it's how I do it okay
所以笔记，这是部分七点
so the notes this is section seven point
这两个计算图和
two does these computational graphs and
然后这里是反向模式，所以它开始
then here is reverse mode so it starts
在这里，我将使用
over here with so I'm going to use the
链规则所以DFDF是一个然后和
chain rule so DF DF is one and then and
然后我会倒退-而我
then I going going backwards - and I
必须使用当然我必须拥有
have to use of course I have to I have
采取我必须找到的衍生物
to take the derivatives I have to find
使用正确的规则所以我必须使用
use the right rule so I have to use the
产品规则，然后很快我将不得不
product rule and then soon I'll have to
使用这些权力规则和线性规则
use these power rule and linear rules so
当然没有改变的是
of course no change there the change is
通过倒退哦我没有
that by going backwards oh I did I don't
知道我是否完成了那句话
know if I completed that sentence that I
可以找到百分之一
could find the hundred partial
如果函数依赖于导数
derivatives if the function depended on
一百个变量大约五次
a hundred variables in about five times
一个变量的成本三到三
the cost of one variable three three to
这样的成本的五倍
five times the cost of one so so that
你会期待一百个
you would expect a hundred a hundred
连锁规则将花费一百倍
chain rules would cost a hundred times
但是你看到我们正在重复使用这些碎片
but but you see we're reusing the pieces
在链中，只是有一个更大的
in the chain and just having a larger
我们的连锁店更宽，但不会更长
our chain is wider but it's not longer
并且它不会重复，所以我在这里
and it's not repeated anyway so here I'm
将使用DFDC和DF的任何东西
gonna use whatever it is DF DC and DF
在S记住，在等什么我
the s remembering that so what in my
是的好，所以DFD是DC是和s
yeah okay so so DF D is DC is s and the
FPS是C因为因为
FPS is C that was because because
因为˚F开始了作为C倍的IT
because F started out as C times s it
是一个产品没关系
was a product okay
那么我们现在必须对它们进行评估
then we've got to evaluate those now
我再看看我是不是
I'll look again to see that I'm
希望写下一些
hopefully writing down some of the
正确的事情好吧现在我已经做了什么
correct things okay so now I've what
我接下来写的是FTC
I've written down next is the FTC is
关于那个例子的五个或者五个
five or no five on the on that example
这是什么FTC是C是X立方
what is it here the FTC is C is X cubed
所以DF哦对不起
so DF oh sorry
DFT是啊我想要我正在寻找s
DF T yeah I want s I'm looking for s
在这里，我正在寻找屁股，所以我
here yep I'm looking for ass so I'm
寻找s，那是X加三
looking for s and that's X plus three
为什么我这样做很好，我想要的
why am I doing this well I I want in the
结束以获得衍生品的尊重
end to get the derivatives with respect
到X和为什么整个梯度好吧我
to X and why the whole gradient okay I
我们认为我们是第一个正确的
think we're started right the first
衍生物是写CNS然后
derivatives is to write C NS and then
让我离开这些箱子打开刚
let me leave these boxes open just to
得到照片然后我会去做
get the picture then I'm going to do
然后我需要DCdXDCDYDsDX
then I'll need DC d X DC D Y D s DX
和DSD为什么我认为这是正确的
and DSD why I think that's right
写在这里我有CNS的产品
write that here I had a product of CNS
所以我需要在这里有两个衍生品
so I needed to had two derivatives here
我有CNS各自区分所以我
I have CNS each to differentiate so I
得到x和ay导数x
get to have an x and a y derivative x
和ay衍生物，现在就是它
and a y derivative and now it just it's
只是把它们放进去
just a matter of putting in those
数字和跟随链
numbers and following the chain
倒退也许我不会放
backwards maybe I'm not going to put
这些数字是因为我，如果我没有
those numbers in because I if I didn't
达到140你不会相信回来
reach 140 you wouldn't believe in back
传播，这就像一个
propagation and that would be like an
愉快的结局，所以我会离开你把
unhappy outcome so I'll leave you to put
他们可能或笔记有一个
them in maybe or the notes have a
你可以看到但你做的单独的例子
separate example that you can see but do
你会看到我要找的重点
you see the point that I'm going to find
所有到最后我都会找到
all the in the end I'm going to find the
FDX和fdy来自
F DX and the f dy from the from the
链从一个链而不是没有链
chain all in from one chain and not not
不是来自单独的链4x和a
not from a separate chain 4x and a
y的独立链是那个对我来说
separate chain for y that's that's to me
这是反向模式的重点
that's the point of reverse mode it's a
一点点魔力，但你看到了
little bit of magic but you see the
这个成分和你们中的一些人
steps the ingredient and and some of you
之前知道也许已经看到了这
know have seen this before and maybe
知道更好的阐述我发现了这个
know a better exposition I found this
克里斯托弗奥拉的博客清楚和这些
blog by Christopher Ola clear and these
你会看到非常简单的事情很清楚
very simple things you'll see are clear
在笔记中，但可能是另一个博客
in the notes but maybe another blog
使得它带来了其他的点，使
makes it brings out other points to make
在这里制作它可能并不明显
to make here it's not obvious maybe that
我可以有一百个变量和
I could have a hundred variables and and
并在四或五个计算
and do the calculation in four or five
将成本计算四到五倍
times the cost for four or five times
而不是一百
being instead of a hundred
是的，但我可以，我也可以
yeah but it's possible okay so can I
今天接近这个怎么可能
come close today with this one how could
那些与你不同的计算方式
those be different your computing the
相同的数字相同的AIjbjkSIque
same numbers the same AI j bj k SI que
eles和并做这个总和，但它是
eles and and doing this sums but it's
当然是不同的所以我们就这样做
certainly is different so let's just do
那好吧我会在这里做，然后在
that okay I'll do it here and then at
正确的时间，我猜它会
the right time and I guess it'll be
在Rao教授和周五之后
after professor Rao and on Friday and
星期一我会回到Fras教授那里
Monday I'll come back to professors Fras
一个收敛的简短证明
short proof of the convergence of a
随机梯度下降整体
stochastic gradient descent the whole
重点是向您展示假设的作用
point is to show you what assumptions do
你需要一些假设
you need you need some assumptions on
梯度上的一些假设
the gradient some assumptions on the
步长，他们是一个很好的证据
step size and they've for a good proof
所有的假设都融合在一起，唐
all the assumptions fit together and Don
得出结论和结论
outcomes the conclusion and the
结论会有多快
conclusion would be how fast it
收敛随机梯度下降所以
converges stochastic gradient descent so
有一些是预期的
there's some there's some s expected
因为它是随机的，我们期待的
things because it's stochastic we expect
关于平均值和平均值的一些假设
some assumptions about the mean and the
方差进入证明
variance to go into the into the proof
所以你会看到，但也许也是如此
so you'll see that but maybe it's too
今天很多，所以今天我只会
much for today so for today I'll just
回过头来，我甚至可以穿上它
come back to that I might even put it on
这是如此的恒星而且近在咫尺
stellar and just close with this so
假设a是M乘nB是n乘P而C是
suppose a is M by n B is n by P and C is
P由Q好吗
P by Q okay
找到一个步骤需要多少步骤
how many steps does it take to find a
倍B倍C的产物
times B times C the product of those
如果我这样走的话我会好三个矩阵
three matrices well if I go this way I
必须倍增我必须首先做BC
have to multiply a I have to do BC first
所以不列颠哥伦比亚省需要多少次操
so BC costs how many operations to
乘上时间是nPQ不错
multiply that times that n PQ nice
公式nPQ为什么我能做得好
formula n PQ why is that well I could
说答案是由Q和
say that the answer is is n by Q and
那里的每个数字都有一个内在的
every number in there was an inner
行和列的长度为P的乘积
product of a row and column of length P
所以我有NQ内部产品和每个
so I have NQ inner products and each one
成本P乘以广告然后现在
costs P multiply ads and then so now now
我有现在的BC，所以就是这样
I have BC which will be now so it's so
现在我有Mbyn然后我有Mby
now I have M by n then then I have M by
n是C乘以B的时间
n which is the a times B by C which is
现在我是Q，这是BC这是ABC和
now n by Q that's BC this is ABC so and
这个花费了M的成本
this one costs what's the cost here M by
由Q同样的规则，即将是M.
n n by Q by the same rule that'll be M
和Q好这是这是第一个方法
and Q good that's that's the first way a
现在公元前第二种方式是B次
times BC now the second way is a B times
C，让我再次写入N和
C and let me write in again and by N and
通过PP的Q，所以现在我先做这个
by P P by Q so now I'm doing this first
所以B费用再次告诉我现在是什么
so a B costs tell me again now what's
矩阵成本的规则
the rule for the cost of a matrix
乘以MNpm和p
multiplication MN p m and p
然后我就把M增加了
and then then I have I'm multiplying M
通过P，这是一个B乘以P的Q，那是C所以
by P that's a B times P by Q that's C so
我有MPQ所以我一起拥有它
I have M P Q so I have that together
与或一起与
with that or that together with that
将这两个或这两个相加
that sum those two or these two and
他们是不同的，让我们放手吧
they're different and let's just let's
只是认识到最重要的
just recognize the most important
例如，假设C是列向量C.
example suppose C is a column vector C
对于列向量，所以Q就是一个
for a column vector so Q is one there's
只有一列，所以如果Q是这样的话
only one column so if Q is 1 this way
NP让我们专注于这一点
did NP let's just specialize to that so
专门用于2C等于列向量
specialize to 2 C equal a column vector
这意味着Q是你只有
which means that Q is 1 you only have
一列，所以然后BC是对的
one column so then a times B C is versus
ABC时代所以我们就可以认识到这
a B times C so let's just figure that
当Q为1时出来，所以nPQ只是np和
out when Q is 1 so n PQ is just n p and
mNQ只是MN，其中B是M和Poh
m NQ is just MN where a B is M and P oh
那已经是一场糟糕的灾难了
that's a bad one disaster already
乘以这两个可能是两个
multiplying those are potentially two
大矩阵乘以列向量
big matrices multiplying a column vector
所以我在这里做了一个矩阵
so here I've done a matrix
乘法我从来没有做过
multiplication I never should have done
这是它给我的矩阵向量
that this is a matrix vector it gives me
一个向量，然后这是一个矩阵
a vector and then this is a matrix
矢量，所以我得到了很好的数字，但我
vector so I get nice numbers here but I
得到一个B的可怕数字然后我
get a terrible number for a B and then I
乘以C
multiply that by C
所以这是MPQmPQ所以MP是因子分解
so that's M PQ m P Q so MP is factoring
因为如果我把它写成n次n
out so if I if I write it as n times n
加上P对比这个是M的
plus P versus this one is M that's
分解时间M不是的
factoring out times M no yeah
什么在这里，对不起，我在做什么
what's up here yep sorry what am i doing
是啊
yeah
它是P从这一个因素出来的因素
is it P that factors out from this one
好吧P次n加M对不起
okay P times n plus M sorry
无论如何，区别在于它
anyway the difference is over it again
或者是，让我再让我这样做
or or right let me let me do this again
如果Q是1，如果我这样走，那就是我的
if Q is 1 if I go this way was that's my
Q为1时的最终总数就是这个
final total when Q was 1 and that's this
知道M因子n加P
that's know M factors out times n plus P
哎呦只是这是哦不适用的因素了
whoops just this is oh no n factors out
对不起n因子n加P和
sorry n factors out times n plus P and
所有这些都是这样的
this way was was all these things
M和P因素都没问题
both the M and the P factor out okay
谢谢时间加Q和Q加
thanks times and plus Q and plus Q was
一个好的，重点是我们有
one okay the whole point is we've got
这三个可怕的倍增
this horrible multiplication of three
大数字，这只有两个大
big numbers and this only had two big
这是他的命令
numbers so this was his orders of
比这更快，当然
magnitude faster than that and of course
你会做计算得知
you would have done the calculation that
你会把这个列乘以的方式
way you would have multiplied the column
通过矩阵向量来获得另一列
vector by a matrix to get another column
矢量，你是乘以那个
vector and you were to multiply that by
获取另一列向量的矩阵
a matrix to get another column vector
在这里，你疯狂地繁殖两个大
where here you crazily multiply two big
矩阵在一起，然后得到一个列
matrices together and then got a column
矢量所以这是有有一个
vector so it was the there's there's a
坏动作好的，谢谢，所以我们已经过去了
bad move okay thanks so we're off past
这个ABC的时间只是为了显示
the time on this ABC it's just to show
那是一个非常熟悉的计算你
that on a very familiar calculation you
必须以正确的顺序进行
have to do it in the right order and
反向传播是正确的顺序
backpropagation is the right order for
偏导数好吧谢谢你
partial derivatives okay thank you and
所以周五携带笔记本电脑并期待
so bring laptops Friday and look forward
to to professor Ralph give him a good
拉尔夫教授给了他一个好的
欢迎
welcome